If you're a type B, be careful.
Leaving it unchecked can lead to potentially
life-threatening problems.
Turn it off!
However, we do have a solution!
This is gross!
It's not that scary.
Want to take a bath?
Will I die too?
You're only six years old. What are you saying?
Ouch!
Sorry!
Bye!
I need to decide on her next nursery school soon or I'll be in trouble.
The big companies where smart people work...
They're supposed to have day-care facilities on-site, right?
Not in this country, though!
Oh, Kawachi-san!
Hey.
Kawachi-san, did you get a girlfriend?
What?
You're going home early these days.
That's not it.
You usually took the last train home.
We had incredible sales last year because of you.
But at this rate...
That's not something you achieve with enthusiasm or grit.
It was just by chance.
My name's "Daikichi," after all.
Daikichi = "Great luck"
Kawachi-san!
Hold the door!
Let me carry that for you.
Ah, thanks!
Fourth floor, right?
Yeah. Feeling good as usual?
Not this year.
I was just told off by this guy here,
and I think I'm losing hair.
Getting good results once makes life harder, huh?
Gotou-san, you really do have a child, right?
Don't go judging someone based on their height!
You're just so thin that
I'm wondering where the baby came from.
I wonder about that too.
He's two years old already.
Thanks a lot. Put them down here.
I'll go with you.
I can handle it!
Okay then.
Later!
She's as powerful as always.
I wish she had stayed in the sales department.
She's been here a lot longer than I have,
and when she got pregnant, she asked for a demotion herself so she could go home at the regular time.
The whole company was talking about her.
How long are you going to take care of her?
I haven't really decided yet.
Rin-chan, huh?
She's been wetting the bed recently.
It looks like she's really embarrassed about that.
It might be a mental problem.
Kids usually sweat a lot,
but since they don't sweat that much during winter,
they have to pee more.
I remember often being told
to use the toilet before sleeping.
Her mother must have had some pressing circumstances.
I wish I could ask her, but I can't.
Mothers are really important, aren't they?
A man shouldn't be complaining!
Just do your best!
What did you do and play today?
I read a picture book and had a staring contest.
That sounds fun.
Why are you doing that?
Rin, I'll prepare dinner soon.
Moon-sama shrunk a bit.
Maternity Record Book
Hello?
How are things?
I'm fine.
I'm not asking about you.
Yeah, she's fine.
Didn't you say something about not wanting to get caught up in all this?
I just can't do that since you really took her in.
I'll come over by the weekend to look for a clue about her mother.
I see. Call me when you've arrived at the station.
Make sure she wears some warm clothes.
I'll call Haruko too.
Rin seems to be on good terms with her kid.
We passed a car again!
Looks like you're having fun.
Yeah!
We're here!
Welcome back.
Nice to see you back here, Rin-chan!
I'm sorry. I don't have anything a child would like.
She seems to like grownup stuff. Right?
You've had enough already?
Yes.
Don't blame me if you get hungry later on.
I'm full.
Sorry for leaving some not eaten.
I'm home!
Sorry I'm late!
Man, that was terrible!
Both the mom and kid are so annoying!
Onii-chan!
You really took this kid in?!
Yes.
Following up, here's the weather report.
It was sunny and clear skies all over the country today.
Temperatures have risen by two degrees everywhere,
which means pleasant weather.
I'm just going to use the restroom.
Now, for tomorrow's weather...
I said I need to use the toilet!
I can't go with you sitting there!
Is she always like that?
Nope.
She talks quite a lot at home.
She was enjoying herself on the train too, like it was a field trip.
It's just that the people here were all uptight at the funeral.
It's not our fault!
Idiot. If adults are gloomy, kids tend to think they're mad that them.
Kids are like that.
Maybe it was like that for you guys too.
See? It was the same for you, in spite of your thick head.
And Rin is a lot smarter than you!
Shut it, baldy!
Rin-chan, you like Cat's Cradle, right?
At least answer her.
Yes.
I'm giving this to Rin-chan.
It's pretty.
Well then, auntie is going to do it, so pay attention.
You're more of a "granny" than of an "auntie".
You don't look old enough to be a grandma!
My, what a sweet girl!
It's just that her standard for "old" is really high!
I'm going to do it now, so watch closely.
Huh? Did I do something wrong?
Huh?
Here's a four-step ladder.
Wow.
A two-step ladder.
An airplane!
A slide.
A diamond!
That's incredible!
This string is easy to use.
Did you make it?
Yes, I knitted it from light wool.
It's better suited for this than regular string.
Oh, right! She can probably juggle beanbags too, since she's so good.
You wind it around your little finger like that.
L-Like this?
Yeah, yeah!
♪ With this one pattern, ♪
♪ making summer clothes... ♪
What's going on here?
It's what you wanted, right?
Coming!
Who is it?
It's probably Haruko-san.
Rin-chan!
They're pretty! What are they called?
Beanbags.
Thanks for coming over.
Higher!
Like this?
No problem.
Also, you're supposed to sing when you do this.
It's amazing that you're raising her while working.
My husband doesn't help me with it at all.
Are you going to Grandpa's house now?
Yeah, I think I might be able to find some clues about Rin's mother.
I see.
This is really easy to use!
It's important for a child to have a mother.
You think I can do it too?
First, you do this, then...
Huh?
This is weird.
Grandpa, you should've at least written a will.
Weren't you worried about Rin?
A modem?
I'm back.
W-What's with your hair?!
I had it done to match Reina-chan's!
And those clothes too...
They're Kazumi onee-chan's.
Huh? Kazumi's?
Mom, you shouldn't put old-fashioned clothes on a child!
Just as I thought, they look great on her!
Well, yeah, I guess.
I guess somehow it looks like a clothes for children nowadays if they're wearing it.
This is so nostalgic.
How was it at Grandpa's place?
You used to wear these when you were four, Kazumi!
No clues at all.
I see.
It's probably better not to get impatient and ask Rin-chan about it.
You're doing your best.
You may not know about this, but
your mom used to work even after you were born.
You mean she wasn't always a housewife?
When she was pregnant with Kazumi,
she overdid it and spent some time in the hospital.
By the time she was able to go back to her company, there was no place for her.
She was really depressed about it.
Kazumi was tiny when she was born too.
She would often take a leave from work or come back early for you kids.
What about Kazumi?
Kazumi was always the priority, which led to her becoming arrogant like that.
Are you going to be okay? Do you want your dad to give you a lift?
It's fine. We have time to go walking.
Can we come back sometime?
"Can we come back sometime?" she asks.
Auntie will always be waiting here, so come back anytime.
Bye.
What are you saying?!
But I want a grandchild!
I'll look after the baby and everything!
I can't raise a kid while working!
I'll lose my womanly charm!
I still want to wear swimsuits and go drinking.
Say, Rin, did Grandpa have a computer?
Do you know what a computer is?
Yeah.
Did Grandpa use one?
The maid used it.
He had a maid?
Her name was Masako-san.
Maternity Record Book
Masako Yoshii
What was she like?
I don't really remember.
I don't like Masako-san.
She didn't like me either and was always angry with me.
She was scary, so I forgot about her.
I see.
It's pointless to say now, but
raising a kid while working is really hard, isn't it?
It's true!
Since you'll always have to take care of everything in such limited time.
Um, Gotou-san, have you ever thought that you're sacrificing yourself for the child?
Are you talking about me changing jobs?
I'm sorry. I know it's rude, but...
It seemed like the best choice at the time.
It turned out fine, so it's great!
But if it wasn't fine, I wouldn't want to talk about it
because words are too powerful.
The "power of words," was it?
Am I being too abstract?
Not at all!
I totally understand!
Please teach me more about kids and stuff!
Kawachi-kun, your kid is the older one, right?
You should be teaching me, Senpai!
Rin, it's okay to wake me up, you know?
But... it's just sweat!
Sweat or whatever, it's fine.
Did you have a bad dream?
What's it like to die?
Daikichi, are you going to die before I do?
The sadness of Grandpa passing away...
And anxiety about what to do if I die too...
Scared about her own death...
Without being able to understand each of it, everything got all tangled up and she can't handle it.
Everything will be okay until you become a fine young lady.
When will I become a lady?
I mean, everything will be fine until you become middle-aged!
Until then, I definitely won't die!
Count on it!
Okay.
And don't worry about wetting your bed.
It'll be fine if you use the toilet before sleeping.
But the toilet is scary!
I'll come along at night.
And if you still wet the bed after that, you'll just have to change your clothes.
Will you be mad?
It's not something to be mad about or laughed at for.
Okay.
What did you want to talk about?
Sorry for the short notice, Hidaka-san.
This may be sudden,
but please transfer me to a job that doesn't require overtime!
What? Kawachi, are you serious?
I'm extremely serious.
I see. So that's what happened.
I personally think it's a waste,
but I've got a kid of my own too.
I'll try to convince the chief.
I'm sorry. I'll leave this in your hands.
The lower ranks are going to make a fuss about this.
I can't accept this!
Why did it have to be you?
You could ask another relative to take her in or something.
I can't tell him that I insisted on taking her in.
Besides, there are nursery schools that take care of kids until late at night!
I don't want to work for anyone but you, Kawachi-san!
Sure, this might be sudden,
but managers often get transferred.
Don't make such a big deal out of it!
But I really am sorry.
My department will eventually settle down even if I'm not around and everything would be back to normal again.
If not, there's something wrong with the company itself.
But that's not the case with Rin...
Or so I think.
My reasoning should be right...
Probably.
Is it done?
Yeah. Is this enough?
Yes, that's perfect.
Admittance Guidebook
Towel, lunchbox,
slippers, toothbrush, cup...
Wrote your name on everything too!
Futon?!
Oh, wait, that's only for babies.
All done!
Daikichi, hurry up!
Right now, saying that this isn't a sacrifice would be lying,
but I hope I can think that way after a few years.
Rin, that thing you have on your towel and lunchbox...
You know, the thing that looks like a big-eared dog...
It's not a dog!
It's a lop bunny!
Lop? What's that?
It's a rabbit!
This isn't a puppy?
Jeez!
Rin! You need to go pee.
I already went.
I see.